<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
        <p>Complete the two tasks below.</p>
    </intro>
    
    <knowl>
        <content>
            <p>{{name}} used ${{principal}} to open a bank account with an annual interest rate of {{interest_percent}}%, compounded {{compounding_times}}. How much money will they have in the account after {{interest_time}} years? Round you answer to the nearest cent.</p>
        </content>
        <outtro>
            <p>After {{interest_time}} years, {{name}} will have {{future_value}} in the bank account. This uses the formula <m>A(t) = A_0(1 + \frac{r}{n})^{nt}</m>, where <m>A_0</m> is the initial amount in the account, <m>r</m> is the annual interest rate (written as a decimal), <m>n</m> is the number of times the interest compounds per year, and <m>t</m> is the number of years.</p>
        </outtro>
    </knowl>
    
    <knowl>
        <content>
            {{#scenario}}
                {{#phrasing1}}
                    <p>At the beginning of an experiment, a scientist has a sample of {{initial_amount}} grams of a radioactive substance. Given that the decay rate is {{exp_percent}}% per minute, answer the following prompts. Round your answers to two decimal places.</p>
                    <list>
                        <item><p>Write down the an exponential equation modeling the amount left in the sample after <m>t</m> minutes.</p></item>
                        <item><p>How much of the sample is left after {{elapsed_time}} minutes?</p></item>
                        <item><p>How long will it take for the sample to only have {{target_amount}} grams left?</p></item>
                        <item><p>How long will it take for the sample to lose half of its amount?</p></item>
                    </list>
                {{/phrasing1}}
      
                {{#phrasing2}}
                    <p>A certain bacteria population is growing continuously at a rate of {{exp_percent}}% per day. Given that the initial population is {{initial_amount}}, answer the following prompts. Round your answers to two decimal places.</p> 
                    <list>
                        <item><p>Write down the an exponential equation modeling the number of bacteria after <m>t</m> days.</p></item>
                        <item><p>What is the population size after {{elapsed_time}} days?</p></item>
                        <item><p>How long will it take the population to reach {{target_amount}}?</p></item>
                        <item><p>How long will it take the population to double in size?</p></item>
                    </list>
                {{/phrasing2}}
            {{/scenario}}
      
            <p>{{Prompt}}</p>
        </content>
        <outtro>
            {{#scenario}}
                {{#phrasing1}}
                    <list>
                        <item><p>The exponential model is <m>A(t) = {{model}}</m>.</p></item>
                        <item><p>After {{elapsed_time}} minutes, {{predicted_amount}} grams will be left of the sample.</p></item>
                        <item><p>After {{predicted_time}} minutes, the sample will have {{target_amount}} grams left.</p></item>
                        <item><p>The half life of the material is {{HD_time}} minutes.</p></item>
                    </list>
                {{/phrasing1}}
      
                {{#phrasing2}}
                    <list>
                        <item><p>The exponential model is <m>A(t) = {{model}}</m>.</p></item>
                        <item><p>After {{elapsed_time}} minutes, the population will be {{predicted_amount}}.</p></item>
                        <item><p>After {{predicted_time}} minutes, the population will reach {{target_amount}}.</p></item>
                        <item><p>The doubling time of the bacteria is {{HD_time}} days.</p></item>
                    </list>
                {{/phrasing2}}
            {{/scenario}}
        </outtro>
    </knowl>

</knowl>
